WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
The
ancient Australian wilderness...
..a place like nowhere else on earth.
And the unforgiving stage...
..for Blood v. Water.
Say goodbye to your loved one.
You're gonna be playing against them.
- Oh, God.
- Torn apart before the game even began.
- Get him, Jesse!
- Brothers...
- Whoo!
- ..sisters...
Mel, go!
..cousins...
Vicious.
..partners...
..even Survivor royalty...
Queen Sandra
taking on her princess, Nina.
..locked together...
- ..in a brutal...
- Is she OK?
- ..individual game...
- Medic! Medic!
..of raw power...
Charging that wall.
..and epic endurance.
Over 50 minutes.
Aaaagh!
Cheers me, my dog.
New bonds emerged...
Joker and Two-Face.
This is gonna be crazy!
..as old relationships
felt the strain...
Don't get angry at me.
Don't try and burn relationships
that I spent ages building.
..and trust turned to betrayal.
I am so sorry, baby sis.
..in a season that delivered...
What do you mean
you've got Jesse's idol?
..the most treacherous act...
Jesse.
..in Australian Survivor history.
What a stitch-up!
It's eat or be eaten.
I have become an animal out here.
I can't decide if this is
worse than being blindsided.
Through painful...
Croc.
..passionate...
- Ben.
- ..and I'm so proud of you.
..and shocking goodbyes...
Khanh.
Noooooo!
..one by one, they fell.
The tribe has spoken.
That was flipping epic!
And now... just four remain.
The commander.
I was a professional soldier.
I won't stop until the mission is done.
The warrior.
I have been to hell and back.
I didn't come all this way to fail now.
The pilot.
My whole game has
been a game of control.
I am the captain out
here, I'm coming in to land
and I'm gonna do what I have
to do to get to Sole Survivor.
The social strategist.
If I had to do a vote now on
who's played the best social game,
it's 100% me.
I'm going for that title.
Four very different games.
And tonight, one will be crowned
Sole Survivor.
Day 46.
Tomorrow is the last
day of this entire game,
and it's done, it's wrapped up.
It just feels so surreal.
I came into this game
with my partner, Ben.
And when Ben was
eliminated, it was really hard.
I was pretty emotional, but
it's given me double motivation
to take this out and
be the Sole Survivor.
I feel like I deserve to be here
because, having been on
the bottom most of the time,
I feel like I've forged my
way into this final spot.
To be the Sole Survivor,
I think you should really
have had to put up a fight.
It's written in the word,
'Survivor'. You've got to survive.
You've got to actually have
put in blood, sweat and tears.
And I don't think any of the other
23 players have fought this hard.
Um, yeah, I'm proud. I didn't
realise I'd say those words.
I'm pretty proud.
When it comes to immunities, I
have won 10 immunity challenges,
three of those being
individual immunity necklaces.
That says I am a physical threat.
It says that I am worthy
of playing this game.
Now the only thing standing
between here and the final three
is today's challenge.
And I have no other
option except for win.
There isn't room for a
second or third place.
So I'm aiming for Sole Survivor
and I'm gonna reach out and grab it.
The winner of Blood v. Water is
going to be decided tomorrow night.
I'm almost there and I can taste it
and I've just got to focus and
make sure I do everything I can
to just get through one
more day in the game.
I've played socially,
I've played physically.
My strategy is one step ahead,
two steps ahead, sometimes,
of everyone.
When I really stepped
into that captain's chair
was that vote on Jordie.
But, you know, I've worked
with a strong alliance.
You have to trust your conversations.
You have to trust your relationships.
You've got to trust the people you've
been working with this whole time.
I'd love to make top three
with Chrissy and Mark.
Standing in my way for
Sole Survivor is Shay.
Everything's on the line. This is
the way I've wanted to play the game.
Now I've got to beat the
challenge beast, so it's a must-win.
I've sacrificed being
away from my fiancee,
who's pregnant with a
little baby on the way.
So, that's priceless time
that you can't get back.
So, I don't want it to be for nothing.
I've got to do this for my family
and the people that, you
know, matter to me back home.
I think if I compare the
Chrissy that I was on day one
compared to me today,
my confidence in what I actually
can do are two different things.
I teamed up with the best
in the biz, Mark and Josh.
Being out here with these
people, absolute gurus of the game,
and I've kept up...
You know, you underestimate
what you're capable of.
I underestimated myself
big-time, coming into here.
If I had to do a vote
now, with the jury,
on who's played the best
social game, it's 100% me.
And I'll back myself
as hard as I can for that
because my whole life
revolves around people.
I love people.
I don't think there's anyone at camp
that loved everyone there more than me.
I think the role that I
had let me go very clean,
without any blood on my hands.
You know, like, I got through votes
and putting people over in that jury
without getting dirty.
And that's clever in itself.
$500,000 would change anyone's life.
It's a ridiculous amount of money -
an amount of money that no-one
would ever see in one lump sum, ever.
You know, it's years and
years and years of work.
Oh, my God.
I couldn't have chosen
three bigger targets.
But if I want to be the Sole
Survivor, I've gotta beat the best.
So bring it on.
Survivor means everything to me
because it changed
the course of my life.
The first time I played,
I met my wife, Sam.
We have a family now and
it's... it's given me everything.
So, the chance to come back
with Sam, it's a dream come true.
Sam and I were the last of 12 couples,
and I could have played
the idol for her and...
..I could have saved her.
But we always said, at the start,
if one of us win, both of us win.
So now I'm just gonna
have to carry through.
Just coming back a second
time, this is redemption.
This time, I'm a far
more savvy social player.
I wanted to meet everyone
and be a trusted team member.
I had a really strong strategic game,
and, so, from that social bond,
I got a lot of information
and it just totally
changed the way I played
and I had space and time to think.
And then, finally, I wanted
to make sure, physically,
I was seen as indispensable to my tribe.
I found an idol.
I held a second idol
for 44 days combined.
That takes nerve, it takes
courage, it takes steel.
I've put everything into this game.
Like any family, we struggle,
we pay bills, we have a mortgage.
I'm playing for Harry,
and to bring him home
the title of Sole Survivor
and the half million
dollars that goes with it,
it would change our lives.
Now I'm at the final
step, I have to get it done.
This is the final part. I've
just got, like, one last push.
The only way I'm
coming off that challenge
is by total and complete failure.
It'll be because my body
can't hold me anymore.
Come on in!
Congratulations on making it to day 46.
You have endured intense conditions
and outlasted 20 others,
including your loved ones,
to make it to the final four,
which is significant
because this season...
..final tribal will include
not two but three people.
That means three of you will
have a chance to pitch to the jury
why you deserve the
title of Sole Survivor
and the half a million
dollars that goes with it.
Now, this is a big moment,
and there's a lot on the line,
so you might need a
little love from home...
- Aw...
- ..to help you through it.
Chrissy, are you ready
to speak to your family?
Hello?
What are you doing?!
Hi!
I miss you guys.
I got a couple more things to
do here, and then I'll be home.
OK. Put the cordial on ice.
I'm coming home soon.
Love you, bubbies. See you then.
Bye!
Oh, shit.
Chrissy, did hearing from your family
remind you why you're out
here, playing this crazy game?
Yeah, that's long overdue.
Yeah, I'm ready to go now.
Alright, Mark.
- Here you go.
- Great. Thank you.
Hello?
- Hello, it's Mark.
- Hello?
- How are you?
- Oh!
Get the boy.
Hold up.
Say, "Hello, Daddy."
Hey, mate, it's Daddy!
It's Daddy! Hey. It's
Daddy. How are you?
I love you, mate.
I'm coming home. I'm coming home soon.
I love you, mate. I'm
gonna see you soon.
No, thank you because,
you know, I don't...
I haven't had my mum for a
long time, so I appreciate it
and you're my mum now.
I tell you what...
- I love you. See you soon.
- OK. Bye-bye, Mark.
So, Mark...
..that's the most emotion I've
seen from you in two seasons.
Yep.
Oh, God, he's a young...
he's a young man.
We left him behind for a long time
and it's hard to do that.
But I came here to do a job
and I owe it to him to get it done.
Shay?
- I don't know who this is gonna be.
- I wonder.
Aw, bless!
Hi, Dad.
Oh... Mum's here, too.
I'm good. How are you?
I miss you so much.
I'm sorry I was away for so long.
- What's up, Benny?!
- That's... that's Chrissy.
We, um... we're about to do...
our last... our last challenge.
Love you, Dad. Bye, Mum, love you.
Miss you.
- Bye, Spuddy.
- Bye.
So, Shay, you gave up
your letter for everyone else.
Was it nice to finally have
some love of your own?
Yeah, I really needed that.
I've been thinking about that letter,
and that's the boost I needed to...
to just hopefully get through today.
Josh, you ready?
- There you go.
- Thanks, mate.
Hello?
Hey, babe.
Hi!
What's goin' on?
How you goin'?
Oh, babe, I found out about a week ago.
Oh... I was so happy.
Oh, my God, I was so happy.
Amazing, babe!
Thank you. I love youse all. Yeah.
Love you, bubby!
Oh...
- OK.
- Love you!
Alright. I'll see youse later.
- Bye.
- See you soon. Bye. Love you, bye.
So, Josh, did hearing from the family
give you the strength you need today?
Yeah. They've given
me a little boost, man.
I know it's the last effort, so...
..I'll just give it everything I've got.
Well, I know you're all dying
to find out why we're here.
Are you ready to get to
your final immunity challenge?
Yeah.
Shay, I'm gonna need it back.
For the last time, immunity
is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you are going to hold onto pegs,
perched over a waterfall.
At regular intervals,
you'll move further down the pegs,
making it more difficult.
As time goes on, your arms will tire
until you can no longer hold on...
..and you fall into the water.
Last person standing wins immunity,
guaranteed a spot in the final three.
As for the rest of you,
tribal council tonight,
where somebody is going to
become the 20th person voted out
and 10th and final member of our jury.
This is it.
This could be a half-million
dollar challenge right here.
Let's sort the spots. Let's get to it.
Alright, everyone's in position.
Oh...
I don't know what's
better - to look up or down.
For immunity and a
spot in the final three...
..this challenge is now on.
Oh...
This challenge is now on.
If you only win one
challenge this season...
..this is it.
All you gotta do is stay up
there longer than anyone else...
..and you will have secured
your spot at the final tribal council...
..where you will have the
chance to pitch to the jury
why you deserve the
title of Sole Survivor.
These first couple of
pegs are the easy ones.
You can take your hand off
at this stage to get a little relief.
Oh, the stretch is real now.
Hands are gonna hurt, shoulders are
gonna hurt, forearms are gonna hurt.
Nowhere to hide in this challenge.
Alright.
You've been on that first peg
for 15 minutes.
I think it is time to
move on to the third.
I'm gonna give you three seconds.
Three, two...
..one...
Oh, shit.
Everyone on the third post.
I don't understand how your
body reaches that bottom one.
You must be horizontal.
- Yeah.
- Pretty much.
That discomfort soon
is gonna turn into pain.
Then it becomes about pain management.
- What a game.
After 46 days out here,
there's not gonna be much
left in the tank anymore.
You're gonna be running on fumes.
Mark, how you feeling?
Definitely locking the arms up.
Triceps, biceps, forearm.
Shoulders.
Yeah, quite difficult.
- Yeah, it's a forearm burner, man. Yeah.
- It is?
Mark? Mark?
How are you feeling, Shay?
Laser focus.
Alright!
You've all been up there for an hour.
Now we're gonna get to
the meat of the challenge.
We're gonna move on to the next peg.
Three, two and one.
- Lots of movement from everyone.
- Oh...
Everyone trying to find some relief.
Chrissy, head down,
trying to breathe through it.
Immunity is on the line tonight.
The tightest alliance
versus Shay.
But it might have to
break tonight, though.
Tribal will be interesting.
We've got some big decisions
to make if I come out of this alive.
- Head or heart.
- Whole game.
But then you put my kids on the phone.
Shouldn't have done that for these guys.
Ah!
We are gonna move on to the next peg.
In three, two, one...
Mark just slowly working those arms.
Methodically keeping it moving.
Chrissy...
..really starting to struggle now.
She's not even close.
Doing everything she can to
work through that pain in her hands.
Ohh!
Chrissy, groaning now.
Really trying to shake it out.
We're gonna move on
to the second-last peg.
Three, two, one...
We're really stretched out now.
Shay, Josh, looking strong.
Chrissy still in it,
despite all the pain.
Ahh...
Chrissy almost loses
her balance. Nice save!
Ohh!
Chrissy giving it everything.
Wow.
Ohh!
I'm going, Joshie.
Hold on.
Chrissy first in.
After an hour and 32 minutes,
she is out of the challenge.
No shot at immunity.
We're now down to three.
Mark, Josh
and Shay,
all battling it out for
that final necklace.
Those pressure points
are taking a beating.
Gotta stay focused.
Everyone giving it everything.
Oh.
Josh really starting to shake.
Putting in a tremendous
amount of work to stay in this.
Amazing. Amazing.
Trying to find some relief somewhere.
Oh.
Let's go, let's go. Focus.
Josh continues to fight.
Josh continues to shake.
But he is still in it.
Oh, I'm gonna go, bro.
That's it!
After an hour and 38 minutes,
Josh can no longer hold in.
He drops. No shot at immunity.
We now have a showdown
between Mark and Shay,
the biggest and the
smallest left in the game...
- Yes!
- ..going head-to-head.
It's all come down to this.
Who can hold that plank
position the longest?
Battling it out for that final necklace.
It's the only way to guarantee
that you do not end up on the jury
and that you end up in the final three
where you will have a shot
to pitch your case to the jury.
Mark is a big boy,
but he is still in it.
Hold, Marky.
Mark really sweating now.
Who's gonna reach their limit first?
Oh, Shay, gracefully doing some
ballet moves right next to him.
Taunting him.
Mark has been consistent this whole time
but he is flipping from side to side.
He is digging deep.
He's clearly in pain now.
Can Mark hold on?
No! That's it!
Shay wins final immunity!
Whoo!
Wow.
Good job, Shay!
Good job, Marky.
Shay, come on over.
Wow.
Congratulations.
Final immunity is yours.
You have guaranteed
yourself a spot at the final tribal
where you will get a
chance to pitch to the jury
why you deserve the
title of Sole Survivor.
Well done.
As for the rest of you,
tribal council tonight
where one of you will become the
10th and final member of our jury.
Won't be you. Alright,
head back to camp.
I'll see you tonight.
Crazy.
Tonight at tribal council,
there's really not many options.
Shay having immunity, it means
it's basically Chrissy or Josh.
It's a hard choice deciding whether
to vote out my best mate, Josh,
or Chrissy, who's been
tight with me since day one.
One of us is going
home and the other three
are gonna be pitching to a
jury for the title of Sole Survivor.
Someone's going to be
disappointed, so there's a lot at stake.
Congratulations, Shay.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I can hear it in your voice,
you're just like, "Screw you."
I just won today's final
immunity challenge
so I'm wearing the final necklace.
That means I'm safe from tonight's vote
and I am a one-in-three
shot from winning this game.
Mind-blowing.
Mate, well done.
- Sorry. I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
- I wasn't in your top-four plan.
- That was the risk of taking...
- Stop ruining our plans.
You know?
- Who forged their way into the top three.
- That's it. That's the whole game.
Yeah. Oh, we're gonna have a chat.
- Yeah.
- We'll be back.
Surely they're not leaving us
together, are they?
This is going to be the
hardest vote for you.
- Let's sit. I feel weak already.
- Yeah.
It feels nice to finally have a little
bit of a comfy seat in this game
'cause I have struggled from the
bottom and fought my way here.
In the top three, I want to be
sitting at the end with Chrissy.
However, now my next thought
is, who do I want to sit next to
out of the two big physical threats,
and they're both strategic players.
So my vote tonight is definitely based
on who I think I can beat at the end.
Just don't speak too loud
'cause they're behind us. Um...
Um, yeah, Mark's my first option.
I feel like he's got so
much up his sleeve.
The ball is kind of in both
our court to do the same thing.
I know.
The only other option is that
they're gonna both write you.
Yeah. 100%.
So, do you think Josh will vote you?
- I don't think Josh will write me.
- So he's gonna pull you aside
- and say Mark.
- 100%. 1,000%.
But you'd be stupid not to take me.
What?
Chrissy was happy to
throw you under last night.
Mm.
And she would have jeopardised
my game if that plan went through.
So you and I load up on her...?
I'm 100% locking in on
her now I've thought about it.
OK. Let's just do it.
Plan tonight is me and
Mark vote for Chrissy
and we hope the girls
get their signals crossed,
Chrissy voting for Mark and
Shay putting my name down
and then Chrissy goes home.
It's a master plan, mate.
Me and Mark, if we stay solid, which
we will because we're tied together,
are gonna guarantee
each other at least fire.
The beauty is about this play,
right, we will mope around camp.
We're gonna pitch that this chat is
us saying, "May the best man win."
"We know where
we're at." We do all this.
Yep. Sentimental.
Sentimental, that's it.
Me and Chrissy have
been tight as since day one
but $500,000 is on the line
and this play is
strategic, it's smart play.
- I'll go and pitch 'em anyway.
- Yeah.
- Pitch your ass off, mate.
- I'll just pitch you.
- Pitch me hard.
- Are you ready for my acting?
Both of us, mate, let's put it on.
So... what did Mark say?
We actually just realised that
we can see the writing on the wall
and it was more of just a chat
- between blokes, saying...
- OK.
..you know, we knew that we're
gonna gun for each other today.
Yep.
You don't wanna give away your plan.
I'm acting like Shay and Chrissy
have my game in their hands
and I need them to
believe that that's the case.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah. Yep.
Mark's game's similar to
mine and Mark's had two idols.
Oh, 100.
He's had idol play,
he's done all that, so...
Yeah, he's got claims, that's for sure.
So...
Yep.
Tonight at tribal council,
there's really not many options.
It's basically Chrissy or Josh.
I've told Josh I'm voting Chrissy
but... I've thought
about it for a long time.
I predicted that this would happen
and I knew I'd have to
go for Josh eventually.
I'm gonna tell Chrissy that as much.
Alright, elephant in the room. Let's go.
I'm writing Josh.
One of the most important
moves I've made in this whole game
didn't last one tribal, it's
lasted for about five weeks,
and that was the decision
to push Josh forward
as the leader of our alliance.
This was my design the whole time.
I knew to get to the end, I had
to have a shield in front of me
when we got to the four.
After five weeks of
putting Josh forward,
at the final hour, the
perceived biggest threat is Josh.
And that's all I needed.
I just think...
..he's a bigger risk and...
..he's a big threat
and he'll probably win.
He does have a lot of things
that he's done in his resume.
Why would I take him? Honestly?
He's better at... The jury likes
him more than they like me.
He's played better.
I've got a massive decision to make.
Mark will not be voting for me.
He definitely wants Josh to go.
Your vote will probably be the decider.
The thought of voting
for Josh breaks my heart.
I don't know how I'm meant to do that.
Goes against everything I stand for.
- So you're not sure at this point.
- No.
- Or you're not...
- I don't even know.
Yi-yi-yi.
Who I want by my side in the
final three and who I should have...
..in my final three are
two totally different things.
I should have...
..Mark and Shay.
I want...
..I think Josh.
But I think all bets are off.
- Like all...
- All alliances are gone.
Exactly. All conversations
are basically dead and untrue
and all that matters is who
people want to sit next to.
I need to switch on.
This is gonna be one of
the biggest nights of my life.
But... for the entire time I've
been on the Survivor journey,
I have absolutely
battled, day in, day out,
with head versus heart.
Those two are my best friends.
So, yeah, I don't know what to do.
We absolutely made...
Absolutely made
our tribe a little family.
Can just about say...
..that blood is not thicker than water
'cause none of these
guys are related to me
and they'll be in my life...
..forever.
We'll now bring in our jury.
Oh, damn.
Khanh.
Mel. Jesse.
Michelle. Jordan.
- Sam.
- Hey.
David. Jordie.
KJ, voted out at
the last tribal council.
Alright.
Before we get started, I
wanna get the jury up to speed.
So today was the final
immunity challenge,
which means tomorrow,
at the final tribal council,
there won't be two,
there will be three people
pleading their case for the $500,000.
So, Shay, no-one wanted
to go up against you today
and I think that necklace
around your neck proves why.
Yeah. Yeah, it was a tough one.
But, um, everyone put in a
solid effort, it was nice to see.
Chrissy, you stayed up
there for a good 1.5 hours.
Yeah, I did. 1.5 hours,
it was pretty full-on.
I think the phone call
prior bought me some time.
That was pretty...
..pretty good
timing, actually, yeah,
to hear from the rug rats
just before we went out there.
What about for you, Mark?
I think, um...
When I heard Harry's
voice, he'd grown up a bit and...
..that was... It was...
Oh, like, we've been
gone eight weeks from him
and, um, it was great to
hear from him.
And he was OK, but... it's just a
reminder of why we're out here.
Everyone has left a lot behind...
..and we have a lot to
play for and a job to do so...
..that's what we're gonna do.
So, Josh, everyone today
predicted that Shay would win.
Do you think everyone's able to
predict what's gonna happen tonight?
Oh, you never know.
It's the final tribal, people might
throw some curve balls in there but,
um... I think it's one or two
of us are on the block tonight.
And, uh, we'll wait
and see what happens.
So, Mark, the moment you walked
into tribal, you looked quite concerned.
If you are being targeted tonight,
what can you do to protect yourself?
It's pretty hard because
a 30-minute scramble
is not gonna be what protects you.
It's the six weeks of game play
that we've had leading up to that point
which is gonna be the
deciding factor for people.
They're gonna look at
what's in their interests
and they're gonna probably
vote in accordance with that.
Well, Chrissy voted for you last night.
Are you concerned she could
do the same again tonight?
There's just not many options, so...
..I understand copping a vote. Yeah.
So, Chrissy...
..can't vote for Shay, obviously
you can't vote for yourself.
The only two people you can
vote for tonight are Josh and Mark
and you've described both of
them as family, in this game.
It's the worst predicament to be in.
And Shay knows, like, when she
won today, of course I'm happy for her
but I was gutted inside 'cause
I knew it was only inevitable.
It's, uh, not the position
I wanted to be in.
I said on day two,
"Alright, him and him."
I don't know how to say,
without swearing, how bad it is.
So, Shay, it is interesting tonight.
With you safe, the alliance
of Chrissy, Josh and Mark,
which has been tight since day one,
will have to turn on itself.
That is a fact.
It sucks I have to come between them
but at least it gets
my foot in the door.
I think the necklace obviously
brought me some time, twice,
and now I'm just lucky
enough to be able to sit back
and watch it implode a little bit.
But it's down to each person
to play their role with their vote.
So it's a gamble. It's a massive gamble.
Josh, do you think your
relationship with Chrissy
is enough to protect you tonight?
I have, uh, all my fingers
and toes crossed, mate,
like I've done my
pitch to the two girls,
and me and Mark have shook hands
and said, "Mate, it's been a pleasure,
"but, you know, we've gotta go
for each other tonight, pretty much."
And, you know, I'm relying heavily
on my relationship with Chrissy,
so... fingers crossed, man.
Alright, well, I think
we should find out
exactly how this is gonna play out.
It is time to vote.
Josh, you're up.
Fingers crossed. Let's
see what happens tonight.
It's been an honour.
Well, here we are.
Gotta write one or the other.
I'll go count the votes.
I'll read the votes.
First vote...
..Josh.
Chrissy. That's one vote
Josh, one vote Chrissy.
Josh. Two votes Josh,
one vote Chrissy...
..one vote left.
20th person voted out and
final member of our jury...
..Josh.
You need to bring me your torch.
Josh, the tribe has spoken.
They have, mate.
- Cheers, guys. Thanks, mate.
- Well done, mate.
- Cheers, brother.
- Cheers.
Well, congratulations,
you three have gone as far
as you can go in this game.
Tomorrow night, the
power shifts to the jury.
So I suggest go back to
camp, get a good night's sleep
and think about how you're
gonna convince THEM
that you deserve to win this game.
Grab your torches. Head
back to camp. Goodnight.
Oh.
Oi.
- Are you serious?
- Keep telling ya, just hang them up.
They were wet, Mark!
Oh. 47 days.
We'll go for our last
little morning stroll?
- Yeah, let's do it.
- Do it.
- Go this way?
- Yeah. Let's go.
This is too surreal to take in.
I just wasn't expecting to get this far
and to get to the final
three in a game like this,
it's the world's greatest
game and I'm proud I got here
and I think Sam will be proud of me too
because she's part
of the reason I'm here.
Nearly home.
I think, looking back at the game,
this has been a lot
about confronting fear.
I spent a long time putting myself
in situations that were horrendous.
They tested me in every
way - physically, emotionally.
- Family's gonna be so proud.
- Yeah.
- Yep.
- Kids are gonna be so proud.
Being out here for
weeks, whenever I woke up,
I thought a lot about the
time I'd spent away, fighting.
It was the first time I was
involved in combat as a young guy.
And I was on a river
that was just like the one
we were sleeping next to.
And in the early morning, in the
dawn, we had to cross this river
and, um, I came up against a cornfield
and we got stuck there for -
in a battle - for about 12 hours.
It was super rough.
I mean, I was only 27.
But one of my soldiers was killed.
Yeah, it's funny 'cause I never
thought about it and then...
..when I was here, every
morning, I had to think about it.
Maybe now when you see creeks like
this, you'll have Survivor memories,
not those memories.
Yeah. Hope so. Better.
Let's do that. About laughing.
About Juicy Dave stories.
I think after this, I'm
gonna see it differently.
I'm not gonna see that same
river that I fought in, I'm gonna see...
..um...
..a camp site where I have mates.
Well, it's been a ride.
- It's been a ride.
- Hasn't it?
- Sure has.
- Been a ride.
Yeah.
To come out and compete in the
game, it's blood, sweat and tears
to try and get to the end.
It's... I feel a real
mixed bag of emotions,
and I think being
here is a sense of relief
and also, a sense of anticipation
because I know tonight,
I'm gonna have to make
the speech of my life.
- Oh.
- What the?
- Avocado!
- Oh, champagne!
- There's champagne there.
- Oh.
I have played such a massive game
compared to what I
thought and when I started.
"Congratulations."
"Celebrate a game
well played with this feast
"fit for the final three."
Originally, I was doing this for myself
but now I feel like I'm doing it
for a whole generation of younger girls
who are maybe scared to lift weights
and they were scared to be strong,
but this will show them that we
are more resilient than we realise.
And all it takes is sticking strong
to yourself and backing yourself.
Cheers, 21 fallen men.
And here we are.
- We've lost a lot of good people.
- We lost some good people!
We lost some good people.
I was a massive fish out
of water coming in here.
Now, here I am,
final three, baby.
Who would have thunk it?
This game puts you into an immediate
state of the opposite
to how you live your life.
Yep.
I've stayed true to myself.
I've been truthful, reliable,
caring, social butterfly.
I need to really tell Khanh
how good he looks tonight.
Like, drop GQ.
And I definitely had
the social connections
for people to just forget about my name.
Like, my name never came up.
Week one, once.
Isn't that in itself a strategy?
35, 40, 45...
47.
That's a lot of days.
This is it. Now we're gonna
play ball for the last quarter.
It's time now to pitch
for my life to that jury.
You know, I've gotta preach
to them why I deserve to win.
And then there were three.
Then there were three.
I'll now bring in the
members of our jury.
Khanh. Mel.
Jesse. Michelle.
Jordan. Sam.
David. Jordie.
KJ.
And Josh, voted out
at the last tribal council.
So... here we are, day 47,
in your final tribal council.
The three of you have gone as
far as you can go in this game.
And tonight, the power
now shifts to the jury -
10 people you've had
a hand in voting out,
either directly or indirectly,
will now decide which of you three
deserves the title of Sole Survivor
and the $500,000 that goes with it.
This is how tonight's gonna work -
you'll each make an opening statement.
This is your chance
to pitch to the jury
why you deserve to win this game.
Then the jury will address you.
They'll ask you questions
and you'll answer them.
Then they'll have a chance to respond
to your answers in an open forum.
Once everyone's said their piece,
the jury will go up to vote
to decide who wins Australian
Survivor Blood v. Water.
Mark, would you like to kick it off?
Just like that? I'd love to, Jonathan.
When I walked onto the
sands of Samoa four years ago,
I came to play the
game of Survivor and...
..I met the love of my life, Samantha.
And it's been a huge part of
my life, it's given me everything.
So we didn't want to be the
couple that had a second chance,
came back and blew it.
I know we all came here to play
in these battles and to fight it out,
but I came to win the war as well.
To do that, you need a strategy
and the strategy I came up with,
it was to win.
Sounds simple but very,
very difficult to execute.
So the first move was
really to go after Andy.
Andy was a returning
player, he was a big threat
and I could have run on
his coat-tails for a long time
but I decided not to.
I worked tightly with Nina
and decided to cut him down
as early as we could in the game.
The next move was the tribe swap.
So when that came, I had
the really fortunate position
to being able to choose between
the new blue tribe or the new red tribe.
And I could have taken the safe option,
gone back to my old blue
tribe, Sammy was now there.
But I didn't, I chose
the riskier option -
red 2.0, we formed a new majority.
We were able to pull off
some pretty cool early moves.
Went straight after the queen, Sandra.
'Cause we knew she was a huge threat.
And then, after we'd gone to the merge,
we had been planning to go after Khanh.
Because you were such a good player
and you had an idol for so long too,
I think the record - 21 days.
The next move was a
real dilemma for Sam and I.
We had to make a choice
between Jordan and Josh
or Jordie and Jesse.
And...
..we made the tough
choice to go after you, Jesse,
because you two are like yin and yang.
You've got, like,
cool-headed, hot-headed.
You're complementary game
players, right, both incredible threats?
And so it was a really tough move
but it was a move we wanted to make.
We were managing a lot of different
parts, including the second idol,
which Jesse had given it to
Sam and it was now a new threat.
That really set up
the final move for me.
For about 30-plus days,
I'd been tight with Josh
and, mate, I had been pushing
you as a leader of our team.
What I was trying to do was make you
a relatively higher threat than I was.
And in the final vote,
the votes landed on Josh.
I'm sure it still stings
but you are my mate.
They were the major moves that I made.
I feel like I have outwitted,
outplayed and outlasted.
When you go up tonight
to vote, respectfully,
I just ask you to think
about considering me
to represent all of you as
this season's Sole Survivor.
Alright.
Nicely said.
Shay, what would you
like to say to the jury?
Here we go.
So... to me...
..the essence of a survivor is to fight.
To actually survive and have
to be at the bottom at some point
and to work their way up.
And I had to make sure the tribe knew,
"Hey, Shay is a physical strength,
she's gonna help us get to rewards."
And I sure did. I tried
as hard as I could
so we did get to a fair few
rewards and immunity wins.
Then merge happened.
That was a huge, joyful moment.
You know, day 32 came
and that was the day when
I knew it was me or Jordie.
Whoever wasn't wearing
the necklace was going
and basically woke up in purgatory.
So to go through that
was... Sure, it was painful
but fought my way back into the game.
I had to fight my way through
and use my physical
strength against all odds.
I ended up with four necklaces,
if you include the one that
Khanh and I got before merge,
which is the most in the game.
I've shown myself that
I am a physical threat.
I'm an absolute beast and could
have gone for an extra half an hour,
hour, in that final challenge.
This whole time, I've
been at the bottom,
actually fighting for my life.
That is why I'm
deserving of Sole Survivor.
Nicely done. Chrissy.
- You're up.
- Alrighty.
Thank you, Jonathan.
The last 47 days have been
the hardest 47 days of my life.
But if you think for one minute
that I left my three babies at home
with no idea where I was
going, what I was doing,
or how long I was gonna be,
you are sorely mistaken.
I'm not here as an accident.
I made my way here on purpose. And...
..I guess let's start at the beginning.
So coming into this, I had one intention
and it was to play a social game.
I've been social my whole life.
I definitely wasn't gonna
be a physical threat.
So I had to align myself
with the best in the business
and I pinpointed them straightaway.
Started my socialising
and started to meet you
guys on a little deeper level.
I have attended more
tribal councils than all of you,
I've been to 19 in total.
And Briana wrote my
name down on the fifth day
and it didn't get written
down again until the 41st day.
My loyalty to you guys, Jesse
especially, shouldn't go unnoticed
and I will remind you...
..I went against my blood and...
..to prove my loyalty to my alliance
with Jordie over the other side,
I went against Croc,
I didn't go with what he wanted to do
and I didn't write your name down.
'Cause I needed to look
Jordie in the eyes and say,
"You've still got my back over there."
With that, ramifications,
Croc ended up going home
and it was at Benny's hand.
So there's no way that
was gonna go down lightly
and I needed to take
my revenge on Benny.
And then...
..there was my number one, Joshie.
What a team we made.
After 46 days,
I've realised that blood
absolutely isn't thicker than water.
And you will be my family,
even if you don't wanna be,
I know you will be my family after this.
But you taught me to
respect the big moves
for the days leading into last night.
And you were my big move.
So I hope you can see...
..why that went down last night.
In saying that, other people on this
jury taught me some hell stuff too.
Jordie, you friggin' taught
me how to laugh again, man.
And in here, we are out the
back of nowhere with nothing left,
and humour is absolutely key.
KJ, you reminded me why we're
here, we're doing it for the kids.
Every day, you'd say they'd be so proud.
I doubted it so much.
If I can take a tiny bit
of each of you with me
to possibly represent
you, as the Sole Survivor,
my job here is done.
Thanks.
Alright, jury, you've heard
three very good pitches...
..it's now your turn to ask questions.
You're looking for information
to make a $500,000 decision.
Alright, jury, you've heard
three very good pitches.
It's now your turn to ask questions,
looking for information to
make a $500,000 decision.
Alright, Khanh?
Would you like to start us off?
Hi, guys. Firstly, congratulations.
You guys, you got to the end.
There's a lot of us that would
have loved to be there, so great job.
You played all very
different games, obviously.
Chrissy, I love you. I don't
have any questions for you.
I love you, Khanh.
Um, Mark, you...
..said it yourself you played
hard from the beginning,
you got Andy out, you didn't make
any excuses about being a threat,
that was known.
I think that you were willing to
make sacrifices, that being Sam,
to get there.
But what I wanna know
was, was that hard?
Because I think naturally, you would
want to preserve your wife, right?
That is a really good one.
When Sam and I sat down to
play the game, we basically said,
"We've got two chances to get to
the end, we're both the same person,
"if one of us wins, we both win."
There was a point where we had two idols
and I had the chance to
save Sam and I didn't do it...
..however, it was a decision we had made
in the cold light of day
before we got to tribal council.
That we're not playing an idol.
The other person will
go back with two idols.
It was hard but that's what happened.
OK, well, that's where I
wanna pick up, you know,
because you sent Jesse over here
and then made ME feel
responsible for Jesse being there.
Tell me why those actions
were necessary to your game.
Um, Jesse and Jordie,
I don't think anyone was on
the receiving end of our moves
as much as you both.
The other part about lying about
the second idol, that was very difficult
but very necessary.
The fallout to that was making
you look like you're a bit crazy.
And I knew eventually,
you would be vindicated.
And you were.
And, um, I do apologise for it.
Because of that decision, I was
able to get more steps in the game.
To be honest, I didn't
care if it was me or Sam.
It ended up being me.
That's how it unfolded.
KJ.
What have you got?
Oh, Chrissy.
You are literally the right mix of
fierceness and tenderness out here
and I know that you would do anything
for the people that you love.
But do you think within
the game of Survivor,
that clouded your judgement at times?
And do you think maybe
putting those that you love,
such as Josh or Jordan or Mark,
ahead of your own game may
have jeopardised it in any way?
Um...
..I think last night, I showed
that I didn't put all the people
that I love ahead of myself.
And I'm gonna have to
deal with that later on.
I got a friendly reminder
from a 7-year-old
that I was out here to
be loyal to me first and...
..if I hadn't have got that phone call,
I don't know if I'd be answering
like this, but absolutely not.
I'm here for myself
and I think that's why I'm sitting
here in a good chance tonight.
Yep. Good answer. Thank you.
Alright, Michelle.
Shay, um, on a scale from zero to 10,
with 10 being the ultimate
game player of Survivor,
where would you rate your game?
I wanna give it an eight.
And I know that people are gonna say,
"Oh, you didn't orchestrate
these massive blindsides,"
but I made it to this final-three
spot, I fought from the bottom.
It isn't comfortable and
easy to make moves
from the position that I was in.
And you don't really have the numbers
and so it's a lot easier for
someone sitting in the majority to go,
"Alright, let's blindside this person,"
and so I'm actually gonna
give myself an extra half a point.
I'm gonna go up to 8.5.
All of you guys, obviously,
wanted to be sitting here right now,
and I did something right.
Alright, Josh.
What question do you have?
Chrissy...
..mate, we had it from the start.
The bond that we built, you're
calling me family, you know,
and we said we were
gonna look out for each other
the whole way through,
the whole game, you pitched
loyalty, family, you're talking about,
you know, "My new incoming
baby, we're family together."
You just threw me under.
And I suppose my question
is just you know, why?
I've been looking into your
blue eyes the whole time.
You were absolutely my number one.
And my social cues picked up
that you had changed yesterday,
and for the first time
ever, we talked strat.
And I didn't wanna talk strat with
you, I just wanted to talk to you.
You were different.
And I knew you were coming
for me so I had to be so brave.
And that's something...
..that I will never forget,
writing your name down.
OK. Um, Marky.
That day after the challenge
when we got back to camp,
I said, "Bro, I've us." We
could have sent Chrissy home...
You know, we shook on it,
we said, "Great, right. Let's go."
My question is at what point
did you then go away from that
and change your vote to me, you know?
Why did you take that option
when I was willing to just back you
and let's go one more together
and pitch next to you, man?
Yep. I knew at some point I was
gonna have to make a play on you.
And I knew when you came up to
me, I felt like your pitch was gonna be,
"Let's go Chrissy."
And I knew at that point,
for the first time in 46 days,
I was gonna look you in the
face and lie to you and say,
"Of course, mate, I'll do it with ya."
And I had no intention
of following through.
And as heartbreaking as that was,
it was a move I-I had to
make at that late stage.
Part of the reason was,
when I'd spoken to Harry
that day at the challenge,
I realised I had a choice to
make, it was gonna be either
going after and supporting my
family or having you there at the end
and I chose my family.
And I hope you understand.
Sam.
- You're up.
- OK.
On this jury stands...
..well, sits...
..some... players who love this game,
who, like, genuinely love this game,
but for a whole range of
reasons, we now sit on the bench
and have the most important
decision ahead of us.
And whilst there probably
is a degree of bias,
I actually take this
role really seriously.
Chrissy, what does this mean to you,
coming into it, to go for this title
and what does it mean now to be
on, potentially, the precipice of it?
What does winning Sole Survivor
and taking the title mean to me?
It will far outsee anything that I
even thought I was capable of.
I came on here, this
is Croc's bucket list.
I came on here with...
..nearly no idea what I
was getting myself into
and every day, I learnt
off the best in the business.
What does it mean?
It means that I absolutely
have smashed it
far further than I thought I ever could.
Alright, Jesse.
What would you like to ask?
Um...
..Marky.
Me and my brother, um, you
know, we were fully committed
to you and Sammy
and you were able to
build a lot of trust there,
uh, which really led to my blindside.
That was completely unsuspecting.
I didn't think that was coming.
You came in here as an ex-SAS soldier,
115 kilo, you're 6'3",
you're a returning player
AND you performed the
first blindside of the game,
removing Andy.
Yet somehow, you
were still underestimated.
I think people don't see how
massive a game you played.
So could you just expand
a little bit more for me
about how managing your threat
level throughout the entire game
has allowed you to sit
in that position right now?
Very... very good question.
And, uh, well considered.
I think one of the ways I did it
was try and be as social as possible
and build tight links with people.
You bring a lot of trust in with that.
I formed genuine connections
with just about everyone here.
Also, really trying to lower
my physical threat profile,
so keeping myself low.
I was on my back as much as I could be.
I was in the water with just my head
sticking out as much as I could be.
And then, the time I was
tagged later as a threat,
I can't remember who did
it, but they basically said -
oh, it was you, Jordie?
You basically said, "Yeah,
Mark and Sam, they're threats."
I was like, "Yeah, absolutely, we are."
And I think just being
open like that is disarming
'cause people connect the dots,
like, "I thought he might be
threatening. He's admitting to it.
"OK, no worries, I know
what I'm dealing with."
And it worked because
I didn't get my first vote
until we were 31 days in.
And that was the longest stretch
of time for anyone in this game.
And so I'm really proud of that.
And I really thought
about everything I did.
And everything I did was deliberate
and aimed at that one strategy.
Which was to win.
Perfectly answered.
And, you know, full respect.
You know, game respect
game, and to be honest,
we still look up to you as a role model
and someone we wanna be more like.
- So I appreciate that.
- Thank you, mate.
Alright, jury, you should have
all the information you need now
to decide who you think
deserves the title of Sole Survivor
and the $500,000 that goes with it.
Remember, tonight, you
are voting for a winner.
For the last time, it is time to vote.
Alright, jury, you should have
all the information you need now
to decide who you think
deserves the title of Sole Survivor
and the $500,00 that goes with it.
Remember, tonight, you
are voting for a winner.
For the last time...
..it is...
..time to vote. Khanh...
..you're up.
I'm voting for you tonight because
you have the right to represent us.
Well played. You played
the most rounded game.
Got nothing but respect for ya.
You are not just my soul mate,
but you are my Sole
Survivor of this game.
I genuinely believe you
have played the best game
and on top of it, it's been a privilege
to have played twice
with you on Survivor.
So... my vote's for you.
Just so much respect for
you as a person on Survivor
and even more respect for
you as a person who's survived.
And it's an honour to write
down your name tonight.
I'll go count the votes.
Well, there's no doubt this has been
an incredible season of Blood v. Water.
The only thing left to
do now is read the votes.
But...
..a moment like this really should be
shared with people you love the most.
Mark, are you ready
to see your little one?
Yeah. Course, Jonathan.
Harry!
Love you.
What are you doing? Hello.
Sam, did you wanna
come over and say hello?
Harry just wants to
say, "I love you, Daddy.
"I love you, Mummy."
- Look, it's Mummy.
- Hello!
- Hello, darling.
- OK, so who's taking care of Harry?
- My mum, Christine.
- Christine.
So, Christine,
are you surprised that Mark
has got this far in the game?
Well, Mark promised me
he'd only be going a week.
One week, Mark.
And look how long - nine
weeks I've had this little boy.
Amazing. No, I'm not
surprised he's done so well.
He's a champion. A real champion.
That was the answer you
were hoping for, right, Mark?
I was hoping... Yeah, and
it's so great to see Harry.
We've been apart from
him for so long and, um...
..it's been the hardest run.
Really, it's the hardest thing we've
done and we just wanna come home.
Well, Mark, we've got some
more surprises for you tonight.
Come on in!
Oh, no way.
I didn't recognise you.
- Where's Mark? Where's Mark?
- You've lost so much weight!
Hi. How are you?
Mark, you wanna bring your family over?
Come on. Come on over.
Come over.
- Can you introduce us?
- Everyone, this is my dad, Robert.
- Hello.
- Hello, everybody.
- And this is my stepmum, Jen.
- Hello.
- So, Robert...
- Yes.
..Mark has said that he's out
here, playing this game for his son.
What's it like seeing your son
so close to realising a dream?
Oh, we thought he'd last five
minutes, so it's a shock, yeah.
OK.
Alright, Shay,
are you ready to see
some familiar faces?
- Yes.
- Come on in!
Welcome!
Hello, gorgeous girl.
- You look beautiful.
- I can't believe you guys came.
What a surprise.
Hello.
Mwah. You smell so good.
- Don't smell me.
- Come here.
Shay, bring 'em all over.
OK, come. Come and join.
Obviously, we know who Ben is.
Can you introduce us to everyone else?
This is my mum, Anne.
She's dyed her hair
extra pink for this moment.
Fantastic.
And my dad, Jean-Marc.
Jean-Marc, how proud are
you of your daughter right now?
Oh, absolutely.
There's no words that can
describe how proud I am.
Um, with Shayelle, she's tenacious.
And... she'll conquer whatever
she can that's in front of her.
Well, I can tell you that
the ballet paid off here.
Definitely did.
Alright, Chrissy, I know
that you're missing your kids.
- Are you ready to see them?
- Yeah, absolutely.
Come on in.
Shut up.
Come here.
Oh, that's cute!
Look how tall you are! What the heck?
- I wish... I wanna...
- Who's that?
- Jonathan.
Alright, Chrissy, we know who Croc is,
but can you introduce
us to the rest of the crew?
Yeah, this is my
little tribe. This is Lulu.
She knew your name,
that's so cute.
Uh, this is Mia-Moana and Essie-bear.
These are my babies.
So, Croc, when you conned Chrissy
into coming out here to play this game,
did you have any idea that
she would make it this far?
Absolutely not.
Not until about, I reckon a week in
and seeing her every
day grow in confidence
and being able to play with
her and be on the same tribe
and see how she interacted with everyone
and how much everyone
loved her and be really proud.
Like, all of us are so proud of her.
So, Lulu...
..what do you think about your
mum sleeping in the dirt for 47 days?
Um, I feel sad for her.
Oh, you feel sad for her?
It's pretty bad, Lulu.
I didn't like it.
Alright, Chrissy,
before I get to the votes,
what's going through
your head right now?
Oh, it's a lot, you know?
We just did the best we could do.
I did the most I could do
with the information that I had.
Had Croc in my corner, had
these guys by my side, so...
- Yeah, it is... It is what it is.
- It is what it is.
It is what it is.
Mark, what's going
through your head right now?
Oh, it's pretty surreal.
I actually wasn't expecting
to have family here.
They've come a long way from WA,
so it's pretty special
to have them all here.
It's what we were playing for.
Shay, what would it mean
to you to win this game?
Oh... everything.
It would mean the respect of the jury,
it would mean all
the fight was worth it.
Yeah, I'm
speechless. It was so tough.
It was so much tougher than I expected.
Um, so to be able to take that
title away is just tremendous.
It's massive.
Alright, let's get to it.
Remember, these votes are for a winner.
I'm gonna read the votes.
First vote...
That's four votes Mark.
That's five votes Mark.
Winner of Australian
Survivor Blood v. Water...
Sorry, mate, I don't smell great.
- Well done.
- Thanks, mate. I'm sorry, brother.
All good.
Thank you so much. I'm pumped.
This is my beautiful KJ.
Can you say hi, KJ?
Good man.
Congratulations, you
are $500,000 richer.
- Wow. Wow.
- Sole Survivor.
- I don't believe it.
- Blood v. Water.
You deserve it, mate. You deserve it.
Well done, mate. You played
an absolute cracker of a game.
You dominated challenges,
you played a really nice social game
and you played a
kick-ass strategic game.
How you managed to make
people not believe you had two idols
I still have no idea.
You outwitted, you
outplayed and you outlasted.
And that's the definition
of a Sole Survivor.
Tonight just shows what happens
when you bring knives to a gunfight.
Mission accomplished, soldier.
You owe me that steak, big man.
I could have written
this down hours ago.
So much respect for you
as a person on Survivor
and even more respect for
you as a person who's survived,
and it's an honour to write
down your name tonight.
Congratulations, and it was a pleasure
rolling through to the
end with you, mate.